字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
It's cold.
好冷
Anything to drink?
有酒嗎？
EPISODE 11: THE GAMBLE
第11集：豪賭
Yes, it really is autumn now.
哇，秋天真的到了
The season when everything you eat is delicious.
這個季節什麼都好吃
Especially the fish.
尤其是魚
Cod, trout, herring…
鱈魚、鱒魚、鯡魚…
Fattened pigs and sheep, are also delicious, commander.
把豬和羊養肥也很好吃，老大
That they are!
確實是如此！
Salted sausages and a stout to wash it all down!
再配上鹽漬香腸和黑啤酒！
Save some for me!
喂，留一點給我
At first I didn't like it, but now I've grown used to English beer.
起初我不喜歡
I like my beer with cheese. That village with the cheddar was great.
我喜歡啤酒配起司
I like the women more than the food.
比起食物，我更喜歡女人
The women here have the goods. Just how I like them!
這裡的女人很優雅，正是我喜歡的！
I know! But aren't they modest?
就是說啊！
Maybe, that's because they're Christian.
因為她們是基督徒吧
Must be nice to be Christian.
當基督徒一定很好
It's become popular lately. Maybe I should convert.
最近越來越流行了 也許我該改信基督教
Not for me.
我才不要
Christianity's has all those rules about what you can and can't do.
基督教煩人的規矩很多 不准這個、不准那個的
Do you remember the wood figure they prayed to in London?
再說了，你們有沒有看到 他們在倫敦祈禱的木頭雕像？
Didn't he look feeble?
他看起來超弱的吧？
He definitely did.
你會受到懲罰的
Yeah!
沒錯！
He was so frail!
他看起來好虛弱！
Thor's hammer would destroy him easily!
索爾的神錘隨便一揮就能幹掉他！
I heard he was a sorcerer.
我聽說他是巫師
Walking on water, creating more bread.
能在水上走，變出更多的麵包…
What boring sorcery!
好爛的巫師！
Odin and Thor are so much better.
奧丁和索爾厲害多了
Now.
好了好了
You mustn't jump to conclusions.
你們不能這麼輕易下結論
We should ask the opinion of one of the Christians here.
我們應該問問基督徒的意見
Hey!
喂！
Prince!
王子殿下！
Between Jesus and the gods of Asgard,
耶穌和阿斯嘉特的眾神
who do you think is greater?
你覺得哪一邊比較強？
What's this?
怎麼回事？
What's wrong, kid?
怎麼了，孩子？
Are you too shy to talk in front of everyone?
難道你不敢在大家面前說話嗎？
Don't get cocky, Thorkell!
你少得意了，托魯克爾！
You faithless scoundrel!
你這個背信棄義的無賴！
Do you understand what you're doing?
你知道自己在做什麼嗎？
Are you one to disrespect His Highness Prince Canute!
竟敢這樣羞辱庫奴特殿下！
I'm not one for taking hostages either.
我也不喜歡抓人質
But King Sweyn has been ignoring me.
但是斯韋恩王一直無視我
I figured if I captured the Prince, maybe the king would look my way.
所以我就想，抓了王子 或許他就會注意我
You must sympathize with my hurt feelings.
你們也同情一下我難過的心情嘛
Commander, you sound like a maiden in love.
老大，只有戀愛中的少女 才會說這種話
Yes! That's exactly how I sound!
對，就是這個
I've fallen for my King Sweyn!
我愛上了我的斯韋恩王了！
You're a gargantuan maiden.
你這個少女的塊頭真大
That's our king of the North Sea.
真不愧是北海之王
He's fallen completely in love!
把人迷得神魂顛倒
What a bunch of lunatics.
一群瘋子
All you know is war.
你們就只知道要打仗
All of you will die!
你們全都會沒命！
How do you intend to face the Danish army of 16,000 with only 500 men?
區區五百人竟想對抗 丹麥軍隊的一萬六千人？
That won't happen.
那種事是不可能發生的
There's no problem, Ragnar.
死亡不是問題，拉古納爾
Have you been Christian for so long that you've forgot what it's like for us?
你們信基督教太久，已經忘了嗎？
The honor
忘記北方戰士的榮譽了？
You mean Valhalla?
你是說瓦爾哈拉？
That's right.
沒錯
The Valkyries are always searching for the souls of the brave,
女武神時時刻刻都在尋找勇者的靈魂
for heroes who will serve as einherjar — the warriors of the gods.
尋找有資格 成為眾神戰士“英靈”的勇者
Those who fight and die bravely in battle
只有戰死沙場的人
will live in the heaven that is Valhalla.
才有資格住進天界的瓦爾哈拉
How to fight
如何戰鬥、如何死去
is all that matters.
才是重點
The stronger the opponent, the better.
對手越強越好
Your beliefs are old.
你真是古板
Really?
是嗎？
A man who runs around seeking only the battlefield…
只會到處穿梭於戰場的人
is a miserable one.
真是可悲
You're a child, Thorkell.
你還是個小孩子，托魯克爾
You know nothing.
什麼都不懂
You know nothing of the royal court, King Sweyn,
你不懂宮廷、不了解斯韋恩王
or my lord, Prince Canute.
也不懂我侍奉的庫奴特王子
What's that?
什麼意思？
I don't get it.
我不懂
What are you saying?
那是什麼意思？
I see it!
我看到了！
The Lord!
主啊！
It's you, isn't it?
是祢，對吧？
Oh, no. He ran out of liquor?
糟糕，他沒酒可以喝了嗎？
-I'm here! -Father!
-我在這裡！ -神父！
Please sit!
請坐下！
-Get him something strong! -Reveal yourself!
-快讓他喝點烈酒！ -讓我看看這些幻象的答案！
Please show me your love!
請賜給我愛！
That never gets old.
每次看都覺得好笑
Goodness! Sure is tough being a Christian.
真是的，當基督徒很辛苦吧？
Hey!
喂，神父！
Who do you think is greater your god or ours?
耶穌和我們的眾神，哪一邊比較強？
Whoever created the liquor.
創造出酒的那一邊
That's true!
這倒是沒錯！
Liquor is our savior!
酒才是救贖啊！
Good one, Christian priest!
基督徒，說得好！
What's this? Why have we suddenly stopped?
怎麼了？突然全都停下來了
Commander?
老大？
Yeah.
好
Let's see.
我看看
Right about over…
大概是…
there!
那邊！
Knew it!
看到沒？果然在那裡
Ambush! On the hill to the right!
有埋伏！右邊的山丘上！
Damn it.
可惡
Thorkell!
托魯克爾！
We've got you surrounded!
你們被包圍了！
We are Ragnar's force, 2,000 strong, commanded by Prince Canute!
我們是庫奴特王子 麾下的拉古納爾小隊，有兩千人！
Are those my men?
我的手下？
2,000?
兩千人？
It must be a bluff if they're declaring themselves.
自己先報出人數的 基本都是在虛張聲勢
Hey.
喂
All right. We got it.
好，我知道了
We are willing to show mercy one last time to you traitors!
我們願意給你們這些叛徒 最後的仁慈！
Release His Highness and Ragnar now!
立刻釋放殿下和拉古納爾大人！
Do so and we will spare you this once!
我們就放你們一條生路！
Think well upon your situation!
好好想清楚自己的立場！
You…
你們沒有…任何選擇的…
to …
權利…
Your Highness!
殿下！
Ragnar!
拉古納爾大人！
This is going well.
很好…
They're more amenable than I thought.
他們比我想的還要聽話
Ragnar's men!
拉古納爾的手下！
Job well done!
辛苦了！
We will certainly return Prince Canute into your protection.
我們一定會把庫奴特王子還給你們
No reason to hold back now, right?
現在沒有顧慮了吧？
Now.
來，全力放馬過來吧！
What?
什麼？
Damn it.
可惡
Stop.
住手
Get a grip on yourself.
忍住
Withdraw!
撤退！
But as warriors, we have no reason to retreat.
身為戰士，我們沒有撤退的理由
They won't run and they don't intend to be captured.
他們不逃跑，也不打算被捕
If we retreat now,
要是現在撤退
all of us will be nothing but cowards!
我們都會變成懦夫！
We have a reason to retreat.
我們有撤退的理由
The prince's safety takes priority above all else!
我們必須優先考慮殿下的安危！
Consider the prince's rescue as your victory!
能夠救出殿下就是勝利了！
Hey, what's wrong, boys?
兄弟們，怎麼了？
You couldn't possibly be scared with 2,000 behind you, right?
該不會有兩千人還會怕吧？
Or is it something else?
還是有別的原因？
Are you thinking about using the hostage as
你們想找藉口說，因為有人質
for why you couldn't commit to the fight?
所以無法使出全力嗎？
How dare you mock us!
你竟敢嘲笑我們！
Stop!
別吵了！
Did you not hear my order?
你們沒聽到我的命令嗎？
Don't let those war-hungry imbeciles manipulate you!
別被那些好戰的笨蛋激怒！
I'm sorry.
對不起
Could it be…
該不會…
that I was right all along?
被我說中了吧？
Bring it on!
放馬過來啊！
We'll send you all to Valhalla!
我們會把你們通通送去瓦爾哈拉！
Yes!
好啊！
If you're ready, I'm at your service!
如果你們有這個本事，那就拜託了！
There's movement.
有動靜了
Right. We can all tell that much.
對，誰都聽得出來
The wind is good.
風向不錯
All right, you bastards!
好，你們這些傢伙！
Do it just like we planned.
照我們的計畫去做吧！
Aye!
-好！
You fools!
你們這些笨蛋！
Protect the prince!
為什麼沒有在保護王子？
Degenerates.
一群混帳
At this rate, it'll be London all over again.
再這樣下去會重蹈倫敦的覆轍
Retreat!
撤退！
There's still time!
還有時間！
Where's the 2,000?
哪有兩千人？
There's only about 400 of them.
頂多也就四百人
We'll finish this in less than half an hour.
不到半小時就能解決掉
What is it, commander?
老大，怎麼了？
Yes, but do you smell that?
你們有沒有聞到？
It's something other than blood.
是血以外的味道
Oh, you're right.
你說得對
I don't smell anything.
我什麼都沒聞到
It's not the smell of guts?
不是內臟的氣味嗎？
No, this is a different smell.
不是，是那個味道吧
Like we're upwind of fire.
上風處好像在燒炭…
Fire?
燒炭？
All right, next one!
好，下一個！
Don't waste time!
別拖拖拉拉！
All right, that's it!
對，就是那樣！
Light it!
點火！
This is not good.
這下不妙
Commander! Where are you?
老大，你在哪裡？
Hey.
喂！
I'm right here.
我在這裡
We're in trouble!
我們有麻煩了！
We're in a sea of flames.
我們身處火海
We can't see our enemy in this smoke.
濃煙讓我們分不清敵我
This isn't the place for a battle.
這裡不適合戰鬥
The downwind is still good. Let's go.
下風處沒有受到影響
We can't go to Valhalla if we die in a wildfire.
被野火燒死的話 就去不了瓦爾哈拉了
A wildfire?
野火？
Someone lit this fire.
這是人為縱火的
This isn't their doing.
應該不是他們幹的
They wouldn't burn themselves to save the prince.
他們不會為了救王子 而讓自己被燒死
Which means?
這就表示…
Yeah.
沒錯
There's a third party
有第三方勢力
It's burning well.
火燒得很旺
Rain hasn't fallen here for a few days.
這裡有一陣子沒下雨了
How atrocious.
好慘
There are many ways to die, but I hope this isn't how I go.
世界上的死法那麼多 但我可不想被燒死
I'm with you on that. It's a painful and boring death.
就是說啊
Though it will be a big help if it kills Thorkell.
但要是能殺死托魯克爾 對我們會很有幫助
Something like this won't kill that monster.
這種把戲殺不死那個怪物
It just a distraction.
只需要製造混亂就夠了
Thorfinn!
托爾芬！
All right. Douse him with water.
好，幫他澆水
You saw the prince from afar, right?
你遠遠地看到王子了吧？
He has a red cape and a helmet with wings.
他穿著紅色斗篷和羽毛頭盔
Remember.
別搞錯人
All right. Go.
好，去吧
Hey, Askeladd.
喂，阿謝拉特
Yeah?
什麼事？
I think we should have joined Ragnar's 400 men.
我覺得我們之前就應該 和拉古納爾的四百名手下合作
Together with our force, we would have equaled Thorkell's army.
加上我們的一百人 就和托魯克爾他們的人數一樣了
We can't win by being equal.
就算人數一樣，也打不過他的
Even if we won,
就算打贏了
Ragnar's force would claim the victory.
功勞也會被拉古納爾他們搶走
It's sink or swim either way.
我們的成敗全靠自己了
Even if this strategy burns Prince Canute to death,
就算庫奴特王子因此被燒死
we can come from behind and feign ignorance.
我們只要裝作不知道就好
No one can prove we started the fire.
沒有人能證明是我們放火的
You say that.
你這麼說
But you think Thorfinn can retrieve the prince?
是覺得托爾芬 能成功把王子帶出來吧？
No matter what you say,
不管怎麼說，你都很信任那個小鬼
I'm just good at using fools who don't know when to be scared.
我只是很會利用天不怕地不怕的笨蛋
What is this?
這是怎麼回事？
I don't think this is Thorkell's doing.
應該不是托魯克爾幹的
Either way, we must go now.
但我們必須離開這裡
Your Highness! Quickly!
殿下，快點！
Ragnar!
拉古納爾大人！
Fool!
笨蛋！
Who thrusts his spear without checking who he's attacking?
誰會沒看清楚攻擊對象就刺過來的？
I'm sorry!
對不起！
I was just frightened.
我只是太害怕…
What would it mean if you had lanced the prince?
要是傷到殿下，你賠得起嗎？
You idiot!
你這個大白痴！
Your Highness!
殿下！
Ragnar!
拉古納爾大人！
Where are you?
你們在哪裡？
See?
看到了嗎？
People with common sense check first.
有常識的人都會像那樣先確認
My apologies.
對不起
Hey!
喂！
His Highness is over here!
王子殿下在這裡！
We're friendly!
我們是自己人！
Please. Make no sudden--
拜託不要突然攻…
We found Canute!
找到庫奴特了！
We won the prize.
獎賞是我們的了
We've found the prince!
找到王子了！
Over here!
在這裡！
Damn it! Thorkell's men.
可惡！是托魯克爾的手下
Looks like I was the fool.
看來我才是笨蛋
Don't kill the prince.
別殺了王子
I know. Be gentle, right?
我知道，要溫柔一點，對吧？
Come over here, dear prince.
過來啊，小王子
We'll take good care of you.
叔叔們會好好照顧你
That was close!
好危險！
A horse?
馬？
Who's this twerp?
這個小鬼是誰？
What's with those glaring eyes?
瞪什麼？
You're raring to go, aren't you?
一副要廝殺的樣子，是吧？
Can we kill him?
能幹掉他嗎？
Probably. He doesn't look important.
應該可以吧，看起來不是重要人物
All right, it's settled.
好，就這樣決定了
Die, pipsqueak!
去死吧，小鬼！
Where'd he go?
他消失了？
You are Prince Canute if I'm not mistaken?
你是庫奴特王子，對吧？
I've come to rescue you.
我是來救你的
Wait there.
在那邊等著
Unbelievable.
真是難以置信
Someone's come to save the prince?
有人來救王子？
But…
可是…
Why?
為什麼？
Why is it always that His Highness is never given a choice?
為什麼殿下總是別無選擇？
Thorfinn! Hey!
托爾芬！喂！
It's Thorfinn, isn't it?
你是托爾芬吧？
Well, I'll be. It is you, Thorfinn.
看吧，果然是托爾芬
I knew we would meet again.
我就知道我們會再見面
Thorkell.
托魯克爾
Commander!
老大！
Do you know who you're dealing with here?
原來你們在跟他打？
Is he giving you trouble?
他很難對付吧？
That's because Thorfinn here
畢竟托爾芬可是曾讓我受重傷的戰士
Look at this.
你們看
Disrespect him and he'll cause you pain.
要是小看他，可是會倒大楣的
But wait, Thorfinn.
但等一下，托爾芬
I must ask you two things.
我想問你兩件事
First, your group started this fire, right?
第一，這是你們放的火吧？
Last question.
還有一個問題
You said you are the son of Thors, did you not?
你說你是托爾茲之子，對吧？
Your father's name is Thors.
你爸爸的名字是托爾茲
Your mother's name is…
你媽媽的名字是
Helga.
海爾加
Am I wrong?
對吧？
How do you know?
你怎麼知道？
I knew it!
原來如此！
So you're the Troll of Jom's son!
你果然是約姆戰鬼的兒子啊！
I can see why you're so strong.
怪不得這麼強
The Troll of Jom?
約姆的戰鬼？
The son of the great Thors?
他是托爾茲大人的兒子？
He doesn't look like him.
他長得不像托爾茲
You know my father?
你認識我爸爸嗎？
Of course I do!
我當然認識
He's the only man in the world stronger than me.
他是世上唯一比我強的人
A true warrior.
是真正的戰士
No!
糟了！
Damn! That's hot!
好燙！
It seems this is not the time for reminiscing, Thorfinn.
看來沒時間跟你敘舊了，托爾芬
I'll let you have the prince for now. We'll do this again later.
王子就先給你了
We're both headed for King Sweyn's home base anyway.
反正我們的目的地 都是斯韋恩王的大本營
If you can evade our pursuit,
如果能逃過我們的追擊，你們就贏了
Don't disappoint me,
別讓我失望
son of Thors, Thorfinn!
托爾茲之子，托爾芬！
Hell.
真是的，托魯克爾老大在哪裡？
Commander!
老大！
Your Highness! Ragnar!
殿下！拉古納爾大人！
Bastard! You're with Thorkell, aren't you?
混蛋！你是托魯克爾的手下吧？
That Thorfinn of yours is late.
他遲到了，那個托爾芬
Seems like you put too much faith in him this time.
看來你這次對他太有信心了
That's fine.
無所謂，反正我們也沒損失
More are coming.
又有人來了
Quickly, move the dead!
快把屍體搬走！
Don't shoot!
別攻擊！
It's me.
是我
I've brought the prince.
我把王子帶來了
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
Because of your reckless strategy, my force has been dispersed.
因為你魯莽的戰術
This is a high crime.
這可是重罪！
They would have been annihilated by Thorkell anyway.
反正他們還不是會被托魯克爾殺光
Keep your voice down!
噓！小聲點！
However, since we can do nothing about this situation,
不過事到如今也沒別的辦法了
we have no choice but to place His Highness under your protection.
只能交由你們護送殿下
Protect the prince and take him back to the army's home base.
一定要將殿下護送回軍隊的大本營
I, Askeladd, son of Olaf,
我，沃拉夫之子阿謝拉特
humbly accept this appointment.
誓將謹守命令
As such, Your Highness…
那麼殿下
as his protector, I wish to look upon the face of His Highness.
身為您的貼身護衛 我能否一睹殿下的尊容？
Your Highness.
殿下…
Prince?
王子？
Are you sure he's not a princess?
確定不是公主嗎？